Ma’am, prepare a treat,
remove the muzzle,
and then give it to him.
It’s alright.
No! Get over here.
Seung jae, stay there.
Oh dear. The poor thing
Stay still.
What about the person who
gets bitten?
What?
Didn’t this hurt?
Maybe just a little.
Be strong.
Think of all the effort
you’ve put into this.
Shall we give it another try?
- Good morning.
- Hello.
You’re here early.
Don’t forget we have training later.
- Won’t you?!
- I won’t.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
Oh, Yukdeok!
That’s much better.
They took them all already?
Sure, they left this morning.
Didn’t even have a chance
to say goodbye.
You know, I love this tranquility
we get once in a while.
All these dogs with broken hearts here.
Abused and abandoned.
Now they’ve found good homes.
Isn’t that great?
Depends on the person.
Tout va bien.
Just leave it to me.
I run a tight ship here.
From Lee Sora
Cheongsan Women’s Correctional Facility
The era of 10 million pets.
Lee Hayoung joins us…
It’s starting.
…to talk us through how we can share a life
with our canine friends.
Welcome.
Hello.
Nice to meet you.
Is there a way to prevent
dog bite incidents?
Yes.
Why? You look great.
Hey, stop watching it.
You were born to be on TV.
You get used to it.
How about a foot massage?
No, not my foot…
Hayoung.
Hmm?
I was thinking about the room
on the second floor.
You said you were going to use it
as your study.
A room for a baby.
Should we try for it?
A baby?
Yeah.
- Wait.
- Why?
Wait. Wait.
Oh…
Dog Owners Require Training
Cheongsan Women’s Correctional Facility
- Dogs are mirrors of their owners
- Dog Behaviorist Lee Hayoung
Excuse me… Can I help you?
Huh?
Where is she?
Hey!
She’s not answering.
She should be back soon.
Will you wait for her?
Sure. I’m in no rush.
Want something to drink?
Freedom!
Do you have a dog?
As if! You can’t have dogs there.
Oh, I guess that’s not
allowed at your place.
Then did you raise a dog before?
Before?
You could say that.
Did I raise it…?
Yeah, I guess.
But it died.
What’s that thing?
This?
It’s a pet microchip.
It’s like a Social Security number.
So harsh…
Sorry?
You heard me.
It’s not a bad thing.
It helps you find your dog
if it goes missing.
Uh-huh.
By the way,
how do you know Hayoung?
Look at my face.
Don’t I remind you of anyone?
You refused all my visits.
Why the sudden change of heart?
Sudden?
I sent you tons of letters.
You call an empty envelope a letter?
Sis, how about a job?
7 years and that’s the first thing
you’ve gotta say?
Sure, it’s your company.
Just hire me.
Do you know what we do here?
Yeah, you train dogs.
But damn, you’re so famous now!
I was floored.
You’re scared of dogs.
That was before.
I freaking love dogs.
Loving them isn’t enough.
This is real work.
So is that a yes?
It’s a job, not a joke.
I’m serious.
Why?
You need new clothes.
Come on.
What are you doing?
- Woo hoo!
- Hey!
- This is it.
- Sick!
This place is wild.
What?
It’s all new.
We turned it into my husband’s study
but he never uses it.
What does he do?
His book.
Read it if you want.
It’s late. Get some rest.
Yes, ma’am.
Don’t close it.
I don’t wanna feel locked in.
You make it sound like
I kidnapped you.
How could you do this
without running it by me?
You expect me to leave my sister
out on the street?
We’re partners.
You should’ve told me.
Tell you what?
That she was in jail?
J… jail?
Murder.
Huh?
She killed someone.
- What?
- Quiet!
I left the door open.
Well then help me to understand!
She stabbed some guy
who tried to rape her.
Wait.
Isn’t that self-defense?
They didn’t see it that way.
Too many stab wounds.
Fuck! You scared me.
What are you doing here?
Wanted to check in on you.
Have a nightmare?
Yeah!
Here? No way.
It wasn’t my fault.
I could’ve died
if I hadn’t done anything.
I know, how mistreated you feel.
Do you?
Forget those bad memories.
Put the past behind you.
Forget…
Sis.
If our house hadn’t burned down,
would we have stayed together?
Maybe we wouldn’t be living
so far apart.
I don’t remember the accident.
And I don’t want to.
Of course.
So you’re saying you don’t remember
what happened?
I want to be human,
just like you.
How do you do it?
Do I really have to run
every morning?
You said you wanna live like
a human being.
You can start by being healthy.
I am healthy.
No you’re not.
Hurry up.
Do I seriously have to clean up shit
every morning?
That’s a trainer’s basic duty.
And you have to
keep an eye on it too.
If it looks or smells strange,
be sure to let me know.
So when the hell do I get to train?
You’re an apprentice.
You’ll be doing cleaning and odd jobs
for at least 3 months.
Seriously?
By the way…
what’s with the attitude?
Chill out, dude.
We’re the same age.
Is it true?
What?
That you’re Hayoung’s sister.
You’re so different.
We’re like basically the same.
I don’t see it.
Guess you only see
what you wanna see.
I’ll be back in an hour.
Good girl. There there.
It’s okay.
Let me see.
How could you let this happen?
Chocolate is poisonous for dogs.
You should know that.
I’m sorry.
I need to be able to trust you.
What are you waiting for?
Get back to work.
Yes, ma’am.
What about Sora?
What?
What do you mean?
Why are you looking at me?
Umm… you’re looking at me too.
Why is my door closed?
I left it open.
Uh… Could’ve been the wind, I guess?
Hey honey. What?
He… hello?
No, it’s just me here.
Bye.
You’re a good liar.
Is something going on?
Feels like
I’m caught in the middle.
Help me out
from time to time, okay?
What?
But I’m not a liar.
Good practice for a writer though,
isn’t it?
I liked your book.
You read it?
You really read my book?
CCTV & Hidden Camera Installation
Suspect Lee arrested in brutal stabbing
of rapist for excessive self-defense
Fucking piece of shit!
Guess I had to press it harder.
No, longer. About 5 seconds.
Hey.
Your novel.
It’s all made up, right?
Sure. It’s a novel.
Whatever.
Still, there’s research and interviews. A
lot of work goes into making it realistic.
Why not write a real story
instead of a realistic one?
You can get sued for that.
Someone should totally write my story.
You were tempted, right?
Huh?
Come on, interview me.
You’re curious about me.
How can you be so sure?
I feel the same.
I’m curious about you.
Hey, Hayoung.
- Could you…
- I got it.
You look exhausted.
What’s that on your jacket?
Have you eaten?
Seriously? On your first day?
What?
A puppy nearly died thanks to
the chocolate you gave him.
It wasn’t me.
It wasn’t?
Shit, did I drop some?
This stuff can seriously kill dogs?
In some cases, yes.
So?
You think I did it on purpose?
No.
You didn’t know
what would happen. Right?
Of course! I love my chocolate.
Why would I give it to some dog?
Sora, I trust you.
But other people don’t know you.
I’ll let it pass this time,
since it was a mistake.
What’s that?
Oh, the wall felt a bit empty.
What do you think?
Whatever. Up to you.
This is your room now.
You get to decide.
Straighten it up…
Sis.
Hmm?
Do you really trust me?
Yeah.
Get some sleep.
Your sister.
She’s not as scary as I thought.
You were scared?
Frankly I wondered what you were thinking
bringing her home. I was angry.
But then I realized
she’s the only family you have.
I think you give her
what I’m not able to.
Me?
Lend her your ear, okay?
But don’t believe everything she says.
Want a refill?
Nope.
Mr. Writer.
Yes?
So how ’bout it?
My story as a novel.
A woman in her 20s
stabbing her rapist to death…
Can’t say I’m too interested.
How come?
Because he has to die.
There’s no mystery.
No secrets.
Ah…
You need a story with a secret.
Why?
Funny story popped up in my mind.
A real one.
Tell me.
My sister and I.
So, what is it?
Nah, what’s there to talk about.
Forget I said anything.
Don’t leave me hanging like that.
If you’re curious, just ask her
about what happened to us.
She doesn’t like to talk about
private things.
Why would you marry
someone like that?
Like it? You like it?
Want some more?
Want more?
Good boy.
Hold on.
Hey! Jelly!
The owner suffered a leg injury and his
8-month-old Maltese sadly died on the spot.
When the owner came to his senses,
the dog who attacked him had disappeared.
The victim’s family filed a police report,
but the dog is believed to be a stray.
Police said they will set up a special team
to capture the dangerous animal.
You’re saying it’s Tofu?
Why are you only saying this now?
You were busy with your TV shows
and we were busy at the center.
I tried looking for her for months,
but I couldn’t find her.
But… that was like… 3 years ago.
Wasn’t it, Hayoung?
A dog trained by a trainer
killed someone? If that got out…
what do you think would happen?
No one died!
But someone could have.
If Tofu keeps doing this and
gets caught,
everyone will know.
Her microchip.
It’s registered to our center.
Right…
You also reported her as adopted
even though she escaped.
I couldn’t say we’d lost
another stray dog.
Hayoung, I had to do that!
Stop clicking that, would you?
I’m not blaming you.
Relax.
Hayoung,
I never meant to deceive you. I…
I did it for the center.
I just wanted to help you somehow, but…
What should we do?
What choice do we have?
We have to catch her,
before anyone else.
Catch her?
Us?
Who else?
I trained her after all.
Mingyeong, have you been drinking?
No!
Well, just one glass.
This is our workplace.
You promised to quit.
I’m sorry.
Why are you here?
You asked me to bring this.
Put it there.
Heading out for a rescue?
Yes.
Seungjae.
You have a dart gun, right?
Yes.
Why?
When I was young,
me and my pals tried to
rob a store.
But there was a dog there.
It was really protective of its owner
and wouldn’t stop barking at us.
But it looked so cool.
That’s when I realized how cool it was
to protect something.
I wanted to be like that dog.
I wanted to have something
to protect like that.
Oh, how did Tofu end up
in our center?
She was rescued from a dog farm.
It was horrible.
I see.
What about you?
Why do you do this?
Me?
I’m pretty good.
I’m a fast learner, right?
Most people get there in a year.
Seungjae, you drive.
What the…
What’s wrong with her?
She’s coming with us?
Seungjae, go that way.
Mingyeong, follow me.
What’s with her?
Hayoung, look, footprints.
Where?
Here.
Run!
Tofu!
Catch her!
Should we get going?
Your sister…
doesn’t know about Tofu, right?
What do you mean?
It just felt like
she did it on purpose.
There was the chocolate thing.
And she messed things up today too.
It’s not like that.
It was a mistake.
You said you guys had a rough split
back in the day.
Can we…
really trust her?
Yes.
Are you mad?
Good work today.
See you tomorrow.
Did you catch her?
No.
Too bad.
Mingyeong thinks
you did it on purpose.
She hates my guts.
Is it true?
Yeah.
I hate her too.
She’s gross.
No.
Did you do it on purpose?
I don’t remember.
I panicked.
But you get it, right?
You panicked too.
So you don’t remember.
Just like last time, right?
Following the recent dog bite incident,
reports of a stray dog roaming
the mountains of Myogyeong district
have been making residents anxious.
The city council has pledged to
send firefighters and
a wildlife rescue team
to capture the animal.
Shall we?
Where’s Mingyeong?
Just us today.
Sit shotgun.
Oh, those… Can I explain?
Sure, I’m all ears.
I need to describe things when I write.
What they are, how they look.
I can’t just imagine it all by myself,
so I need a model.
You need ingredients
to make something.
So what d’you make?
Nothing just yet.
I’ll delete them all.
Could you keep it a secret
from Hayoung?
What’s in it for me?
I’m gonna take a look around.
Stay here.
Don’t go too far.
It’s dangerous.
For me, or you?
I’ll be back.
Sis.
I wish I was stronger.
You know, it’s my first time
drinking here since we moved in.
Huh?
Are you for real?
No f-ing way I could hold back.
Cheers.
Thank you.
Hayoung and I used to do this
all the time.
I think she knows.
She’s not taking the bait.
Let’s give it a minute.
I knew you’d come.
Don’t close it.
Hayoung’s not coming home today.
Wide open!
Why didn’t you wake me?
Hang on, I’ll do it.
It’s almost done.
Sleep well?
Yeah.
You were snoring.
Really? I’m sorry.
Guess you couldn’t sleep.
Just kidding.
How about a date tonight?
A date, tonight? Us?
Sure, why?
Don’t want to?
I do,
but I came up with a good idea
for my book.
Want to submit by the end of month,
so my mind’s in a state.
Good for you.
Sudden flash of inspiration?
Yeah, feeling good about it.
Hand me a plate.
Sure.
What’s with the smile?
I haven’t seen you excited like this
in a long time.
Am I?
Looking forward to it.
Break a leg.
Are you going to put her down?
You know our center’s against that.
Got any other ideas?
She’ll be euthanized
no matter who catches her.
But…
Right away?
We’re not going to kill her.
She’s made it this far,
alone in the mountain.
So what’s your plan?
Are you gonna raise her?
You know I can’t.
Others would find out.
We’re the only people
who come in here.
I’ll make sure
no one else comes inside.
Hayoung.
How did you know?
Know what?
That I want to train her again.
It just…
seemed obvious while watching you.
Don’t watch me anymore.
Sorry?
You said you were watching me.
I don’t like being watched.
Oh.
Okay.
How could you do that
without consulting me?
You embarrassed me
in front of a coworker.
Why are you staring at me like that?
Am I wrong?
I tried to wake you yesterday,
but you were out cold.
You were hammered.
Our apprentices saw you.
Huh?
I guess you’ve been on edge
because of Tofu.
And you’ve been working hard.
We caught Tofu,
so it’s all settled now.
What’s the problem?
It’s not that.
It’s you and me.
Why are you so distant these days?
Each time you stare at me like that… I…
I don’t know what to do.
There’s no “what” to it.
Just do what you have to do.
Or throw in the towel.
Stick it out till the end.
Look how soft your hair is now.
Be still!
What are you smiling about?
Remember?
You used to tie my hair like this
when we were kids.
Your hair was so soft,
felt nice to touch it.
When I stroked your hair
you would fall right asleep.
Cut it out. That tickles.
And now…
that little girl’s all grown up.
What do you mean?
Oh you know. Isn’t it funny
that we live together now?
Funny?
I guess.
Not what I expected either.
Happy birthday to you.
Happy birthday, dear Sora.
Happy birthday.
Thanks for being here
Hurry up.
The candle’s melting.
You’re pretty fast.
Hardly.
Ta-da!
You bought booze?
What’s gotten into you?
Can’t have a party without booze.
Do you like to drink?
Of course.
Will this be enough?
I’ve been meaning to ask you
something.
Let’s drink tonight.
What is it?
Why did you scream and
run away the other day?
Oh…
It just reminded me of something.
What?
When I was young,
I saw a wild dog at night.
Oh, you were traumatized.
But it wasn’t a dog.
What was it?
A person.
Should I go buy some booze?
Yeah, sure.
What do you like?
Liquor for me.
Liquor!
Having fun?
Sure, join us.
Why are you out here alone?
This is fun too.
Can I join you?
Why not.
It’s like watching a play, isn’t it?
You’re giving them a ride?
Yeah, I didn’t drink.
Throw a blanket over Sora.
She’ll catch a cold.
Huh?
Let’s go.
Good night.
Get home safe.
Au revoir.
- See you in a bit.
- Yeah, drive safe.
Hayoung.
Yes?
Aren’t Yoonho and Sora
a bit too close?
It’s nice for a family to be close.
Seungjae, do you mind
if I drop her off first?
Sure.
Me? Go home?
No way, I’m not going home.
Stop. Here, let me out here.
Is it alright to leave her?
I’m just glad to be rid of her.
Huh?
Shall we get some fresh air?
Yes, I’d like that.
Cut it out!
I told you. Don’t do that.
Is that funny?
What’s the big deal?
Hayoung does it all the time.
But I can’t?
Sisters Survive House Fire
1998 Fire Started by Playing Children
Sisters Left Behind by Father
House Fire Started by Candle
What are you doing?
Why are you reading all this?
Hayoung, calm down.
Just hear me out.
Is your book about me?
Is that a problem?
That’s my story.
It’s not just your story.
Besides, it’s only a grain of inspiration.
Oh, come on!
It’s my novel.
I don’t need anyone’s permission!
Don’t write it.
Got that?
Don’t tell me what to do.
What are you playing at?
Aren’t you curious?
What others thought about that day?
We were playing with fire.
What’s there to think about?
We?
Why d’you teach me
how to start a fire that day?
Why d’you leave me and run away?
What did you come here for?
You’re really lucky, you know?
Living such a good life
after killing someone.
What are you talking about?
Sis, I learned
all my tricks from you.
No!
Good girl.
Attagirl.
Gonna let you off now. It’s okay.
Wanna go out?
I wish I could let you.
Oh, Hayoung.
Hey!
Aw, thanks.
I’m so thirsty.
Get it together. Come on!
Hey, you’re here early.
Yeah.
Hello.
- Our CEO.
- Nice to meet you.
Have you read it already?
It’s only been a day.
Oh, your book?
Why horror all of a sudden?
What did you think?
You can be honest.
Actually, we called you in to talk about
a different project, not your book.
Is there anything to discuss
besides my book?
Well, we’d like you to write
essays for our website.
Essays? Me?
Your wife is trainer Lee Hayoung.
I’m a big fan of hers.
I heard you met during an interview,
fell in love and got married.
So?
Basically, you’d write about
your daily life
as a stay-at-home novelist
married to a famous dog trainer.
What?
Come on, you’re good at this.
It’s like a romantic diary.
You used to blog all the time.
That was years ago.
I stopped after my debut novel.
If your essays are well received,
it could be a big help for your next book.
So, how about it?
Hello, everyone. I’m Lee Hayoung
from the Gureum Training Center.
We’ll start with clicker training.
Our friends need to know
this sound means “well done”, okay?
Yes!
So…
Byeol, look at that!
Hailey, touch.
Do you all have your clickers?
Yes.
Let’s split up into groups
and start the clicker training.
Yes.
Give them a hand.
The group session will last 20 minutes.
You’re a little close together.
Give yourselves some room.
Good.
You’re doing great.
Hello, ma’am.
Hello.
How have you been?
I’m not going to give up on him.
Start by believing in yourself.
Okay, I’ll try.
I’ll help you.
Wanna go for a walk?
Walkies!
You have to keep at it.
It’s okay. Don’t worry.
What’s that?
Oh my god!
Let’s go!
Take a rest.
Thank you.
Why are you here?
Don’t be like that.
What’s with you?
It hurts to see you like this.
My, look how sensitive you are.
You mean it, right?
Fuck off.
You fucking dog.
Ah, you’re home.
Where’s Hayoung?
You know she’s in the hospital.
Who gets hospitalized for
a little nibble?
Such a drama queen.
And whose fault is that?
It’s my fault, right?
I bit her.
You know what’s inside
that warehouse at the center?
See the news?
About that wild dog?
Now that one really bit someone.
And if it kills someone,
it’ll be a killer dog.
So Hayoung will be the trainer
who trained a killer dog.
I’m not drinking.
It’s an idea for your book.
Not interested.
Then how about this.
Wanna run away with me?
Or write about mooching off my sister.
What?
It’s true.
You can’t write a word
without her permission.
You think I’m pathetic?
What?
You’re the one who’s pathetic.
The secret behind the blaze,
the older sister killing her father
and setting the fire.
I wrote about that.
But it didn’t make any sense.
She had no reason to kill her father.
I saw it with my own eyes.
That’s not important.
I’m talking about
the logic of the story.
When you look at it all together
there’s only one solution.
The younger sister killed him
and pretends otherwise.
Why?
Because she wants to blame others.
She feels…
her life has been unfair.
You don’t know a thing about me.
Of course not.
I would just write it that way.
I deactivated Tofu’s microchip.
There’s no evidence that
she was trained by you.
Maybe we should free her
back into the mountains?
I’m not sure what to do next.
Seungjae, why are you
so eager to save her?
I want to see.
If she can really change.
Why are you smiling?
Let’s go.
Yoonho?
Yoonho!
Hello?
Hey!
- Let go!
- Are you nuts?
Get off!
Let go of it!
Give it to me!
Sora.
Put it down.
Sora, listen to me.
Why would I listen to you?
So what’s your plan?
How do you get away with this?
He’s still alive. He’s not dead.
This is an accident. Okay?
Let’s call 911 right now.
Then what about me?
Am I going inside again?
I’ll help you.
We’ll go to the police together.
Why is it always me
who gets punished!
No! It’s not like that.
It’s okay.
It’ll all be okay.
I’ll wait for you.
I waited for you,
but you never came.
I was scared too then.
- I was so young.
- I was younger!
You had me!
I had no one.
I’ll sort it out with Yoonho.
They’ll take that into consideration.
Just endure it for a little while
and come back.
I’ll be right here.
Sora!
Lee Sora!